Shantanu Saxena

(+44) 07469013006 | shantanu17sept@gmail.com HA1 3BS, London, United Kingdom | GitHub | LinkedIn | YouTube

Summary

Highly trained and experienced penetration tester specializing in Network, Web Application/API security, and Automation. Proficient in identifying and addressing complex vulnerabilities. Contributor to cybersecurity blogs on Medium and creator of TryHackMe and HackTheBox walkthrough videos on YouTube. Consistently ranked within the top 30-100 in national and international Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions. Discovered a low-medium severity user enumeration vulnerability in a public CRM (CVE pending).

Experience

Security Researcher (Freelance)

01/11/2021 - 30/09/2023

- Conducted bug bounty hunting on public and private web infrastructure using tools like Burp Suite, ffuf, Kiterunner, aws-cli, and sqlmap.
- Discovered a medium severity 0-day vulnerability in a public CRM (CVE pending).
- Automated asset discovery and initial enumeration for API endpoints, JS files, subdomains, and directories using Python and Bash scripting.

Cyber Security Consultant @ ASTRA CYBER TECH

01/12/2022 - 01/05/2023

- Conducted penetration tests on network infrastructure, web, and mobile applications for BFSI clients, simulating real-world attacks.
- Analyzed security systems to identify risks and gaps.
- Prepared detailed vulnerability reports and recommended remediation steps.
- Participated in security incident response.

Information Security Analyst @ W-CYBERTEAM

01/03/2022 - 30/11/2022

- Performed vulnerability assessments and penetration testing on network, web, and mobile applications.
- · Conducted technical interviews as part of the hiring team.
- Trained and mentored new interns.

Skills

Penetration Testing	Web Application Security	API Security	Red Teaming
Source Code Analysis	OSINT	Python	Bash
PowerShell	Git	Burp Suite	Nmap
Metasploit	SQLMap	Postman	

Certifications

- eWPTX (eLearnSecurity Web Application Penetration Testing Extreme)
- eWPT (eLearnSecurity Web Application Penetration Testing)
- eJPT (eLearnSecurity Junior Penetration Tester)

Publications

- "Non-Alphanumeric Payloads for XSS and How they work." (2022)
- "A Pentester's dive into Kerberos" (2022)
- "eWPT exam Review and Study Guide!" (2021)

CTF Accomplishments

- World Rank 30, CyberApocalyse-CTF (2023)
- World Rank 75, Hacktober-CTF (2020)
- World Rank 98 & National Rank 7, b01liers-CTF
- National Rank 20, Sector:443-CTF
- National Rank 75, Affinity-CTF (2020)

Education

Master of Science - Cyber Security @ Northumbria University - London

07/05/2024 - Current | https://london.northumbria.ac.uk/

Research: Created an ML model to detect Golden and Silver Ticket attacks using klist output, random forest, and pandas library with Python and PowerShell.

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science & Engineering @ Kalinga Institute Of Industrial Technology

01/06/2016 - 01/06/2020 | https://kiit.ac.in/